{
  "GST 101": [
    {
      "question": "The Green color in the Nigerian flag stands for:",
      "options": ["Wealth", "Peace", "Agriculture", "Oil"],
      "correctAnswer": "Agriculture"
    },
    {
      "question": "The official Nigerian national pledge ends with the words:",
      "options": ["So help me God", "In God we trust", "Long live Nigeria", "One nation bound in freedom"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "So help me God"
    },
    {
      "question": "The 1999 Constitution of Nigeria provides for how many tiers of government?",
      "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "The capital of Nigeria is:",
      "options": ["Lagos", "Port Harcourt", "Abuja", "Kano"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Abuja"
    },
    {
      "question": "Civic responsibility includes all except:",
      "options": ["Voting", "Tax evasion", "Obeying laws", "National service"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Tax evasion"
    },
    {
      "question": "The body responsible for conducting elections in Nigeria is:",
      "options": ["EFCC", "INEC", "ICPC", "NCC"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "INEC"
    },
    {
      "question": "Democracy is best defined as government:",
      "options": [
        "By the rich",
        "By military",
        "Of the people, by the people, for the people",
        "Of kings and rulers"
      ],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Of the people, by the people, for the people"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is NOT a symbol of national identity?",
      "options": ["National flag", "National anthem", "Driver’s license", "Coat of arms"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Driver’s license"
    },
    {
      "question": "The motto on the Nigerian Coat of Arms is:",
      "options": [
        "Unity and Progress",
        "Peace and Unity",
        "Unity and Faith, Peace and Progress",
        "Justice and Honor"
      ],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Unity and Faith, Peace and Progress"
    },
    {
      "question": "Citizenship by birth in Nigeria is based on:",
      "options": ["Place of birth only", "Tribe only", "Parentage", "Voting right"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Parentage"
    },
    {
      "question": "Conflict is best described as:",
      "options": ["Peace agreement", "A misunderstanding", "Disagreement between parties", "A legal document"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Disagreement between parties"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these promotes peace in a society?",
      "options": ["Tribalism", "Dialogue", "Violence", "Election rigging"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Dialogue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ethnic conflict in Nigeria can be reduced through:",
      "options": ["Ethnic bias", "Segregation", "National integration", "War"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "National integration"
    },
    {
      "question": "The full meaning of ECOWAS is:",
      "options": [
        "Economic Cooperation of West Africa States",
        "Economic Community of West African States",
        "Economic Countries of West Africa",
        "Ecological Committee of West Africa"
      ],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Economic Community of West African States"
    },
    {
      "question": "A major cause of conflict in Nigeria is:",
      "options": ["Peace treaties", "Inter-ethnic tolerance", "Religious intolerance", "Infrastructure development"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Religious intolerance"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following helps foster national unity?",
      "options": ["Nepotism", "Corruption", "NYSC", "Tribal wars"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "NYSC"
    },
    {
      "question": "Peace education helps students to learn about:",
      "options": ["Fighting rights", "Gun use", "Conflict resolution", "Political violence"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Conflict resolution"
    },
    {
      "question": "The opposite of peace is:",
      "options": ["Progress", "Unity", "Conflict", "Growth"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Conflict"
    },
    {
      "question": "The civil war in Nigeria lasted from:",
      "options": ["1960–1965", "1967–1970", "1970–1975", "1980–1983"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "1967–1970"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which agency is responsible for peace and conflict resolution in Nigeria?",
      "options": ["INEC", "EFCC", "National Peace Commission", "NYSC"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "National Peace Commission"
    },
    {
      "question": "Effective communication requires a:",
      "options": ["Loud voice", "Clear message", "Long message", "Complex language"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Clear message"
    },
    {
      "question": "A formal letter should end with:",
      "options": ["Cheers", "Lots of love", "Yours faithfully", "Catch you later"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Yours faithfully"
    },
    {
      "question": "The plural of “crisis” is:",
      "options": ["Crises", "Crisises", "Criseses", "Crisis"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Crises"
    },
    {
      "question": "Listening attentively during a lecture demonstrates:",
      "options": ["Passive attitude", "Inefficiency", "Good communication skill", "Rebellion"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Good communication skill"
    },
    {
      "question": "A speech that persuades people to take action is called:",
      "options": ["Narrative", "Descriptive", "Argumentative", "Persuasive"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Persuasive"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is NOT a barrier to effective communication?",
      "options": ["Noise", "Clarity", "Language difference", "Distraction"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Clarity"
    },
    {
      "question": "A well-organized essay should have:",
      "options": ["Only introduction", "Only body", "Introduction, body, and conclusion", "Only conclusion"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Introduction, body, and conclusion"
    },
    {
      "question": "The tone of a formal letter is usually:",
      "options": ["Friendly", "Polite and respectful", "Joking", "Sarcastic"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Polite and respectful"
    },
    {
      "question": "The part of speech that names a person, place, or thing is called:",
      "options": ["Verb", "Adverb", "Pronoun", "Noun"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Noun"
    },
    {
      "question": "The main purpose of communication is to:",
      "options": ["Confuse", "Inform and connect", "Entertain only", "Show power"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Inform and connect"
    },
    {
      "question": "A good leader must possess the quality of:",
      "options": ["Pride", "Arrogance", "Integrity", "Corruption"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Integrity"
    },
    {
      "question": "Corruption affects development by:",
      "options": ["Encouraging growth", "Building trust", "Draining resources", "Uniting people"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Draining resources"
    },
    {
      "question": "National development includes:",
      "options": ["Political, economic and social progress", "Individual interest only", "Military takeover", "Tribal domination"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Political, economic and social progress"
    },
    {
      "question": "The agency fighting corruption in Nigeria is:",
      "options": ["NCC", "EFCC", "WAEC", "NIMC"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "EFCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "Leadership by example means:",
      "options": ["Leading through fear", "Delegating wrongly", "Doing what you ask others to do", "Avoiding responsibility"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Doing what you ask others to do"
    },
    {
      "question": "Poor leadership leads to:",
      "options": ["National growth", "Social unrest", "Effective governance", "Increased education"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Social unrest"
    },
    {
      "question": "NYSC was introduced in the year:",
      "options": ["1960", "1973", "1980", "1999"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "1973"
    },
    {
      "question": "One key goal of NYSC is to:",
      "options": ["Separate youth by tribe", "Encourage military training", "Promote national unity", "Reduce job creation"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Promote national unity"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a leadership style?",
      "options": ["Autocratic", "Reactive", "Exploitative", "Erratic"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Autocratic"
    },
    {
      "question": "Vision 2020 was aimed at making Nigeria:",
      "options": ["A war-free country", "A developed economy", "A religious state", "A one-party state"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "A developed economy"
    },
    {
      "question": "Entrepreneurship is defined as:",
      "options": ["Working under a boss", "Establishing a business and taking risks", "Avoiding job responsibilities", "Waiting for employment"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Establishing a business and taking risks"
    },
    {
      "question": "A successful entrepreneur must:",
      "options": ["Avoid innovation", "Depend on luck", "Be risk-averse", "Be creative"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Be creative"
    },
    {
      "question": "Business ethics means:",
      "options": ["Cheating customers", "Abusing employees", "Doing business legally and fairly", "Bribing officials"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Doing business legally and fairly"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is an unethical business practice?",
      "options": ["Honesty", "Transparency", "Fraud", "Accountability"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Fraud"
    },
    {
      "question": "Entrepreneurship helps national development by:",
      "options": ["Discouraging innovation", "Reducing employment", "Creating jobs", "Increasing crime"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Creating jobs"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ethics in the workplace promotes:",
      "options": ["Laziness", "Distrust", "Integrity and responsibility", "Disobedience"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Integrity and responsibility"
    },
    {
      "question": "Entrepreneurs are important because they:",
      "options": ["Spend resources", "Generate employment", "Avoid tax", "Depend on foreign aid"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Generate employment"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is NOT an entrepreneur trait?",
      "options": ["Innovation", "Passion", "Insecurity", "Risk-taking"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Insecurity"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of Nigeria’s major problems in development is:",
      "options": ["Technological advancement", "Resource management", "Good roads", "Adequate education"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Resource management"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ethical business practices lead to:",
      "options": ["National disorder", "Legal punishment", "Sustainable development", "Customer loss"],
      "correctcorrectAnswer": "Sustainable development"
    }
  ]
}
